Track 2: Work Being a Drag? (tentative)
Hm?
Wait a minute, Sensei,
are you trying to pretend not to notice?
That's pretty mean.
I made the arduous journey of coming all the way to Schale,
You're really not going to take even a peek at your cute little student
and just keep working?
Do you always brush everyone off like this when you're busy?
If not that...
Am I the only one you act like this around,
perhaps?
まあ、意地をはるならはるで、構いませんよ。
それを堕落させるために、こうして来ているわけですからね。
With that said, well...
I'm here to woo you over,
not be mean to you.
So...
If you really don't like this,
I won't get in your way.
But...
It doesn't look like you've moved your pen for a while now.
Is something wrong, Sensei?
Of course, if you're really in a pinch,
I wouldn't mind helping you out.
As a fellow middle manager myself,
I share your pain.
At the very least,
I think I should be able to relate more than others.
But, Sensei...
先ほどから、少しモニターを見てはスマホを取り出し
ちょっとキーボードを叩いては
staring at the ceiling...
It looks like you're not very focused on the work at hand.
Or maybe...
your ability to concentrate has reached its limit?
I know how you feel.
If you're tired, not being able to move your hand
is just a matter of fact.
You're tired of working, right?
やる気は待ってても来ないもの、
そのやる気を出すには、手を動かすことから〜
などと言いますが
そうして最初の一歩を踏み出すのは
is always the toughest part.
At times like those
there's nothing you can do.
How about it, Sensei?
Why don't we go over there and take a nice little break?
There's no one around.
It's the perfect opportunity.
I'm sure your body is exhausted.
How about we go stretch yourself out on that sofa?
Don't worry about it.
It's just a few minutes of relaxation.
Nobody will yell at you for that.
Here, the only one who has eyes on you is me.
I guess I have no choice.
I'll even add a special service on top.
中間管理職同士の好で
優しくしてあげますよ
I'll even feed you a little snack with this very hand.
And if you do what I'm telling you to do now,
私も先生の言うこと
聞いてあげてもいいですone thing of your bidding
Just one, though, okay?
you might get motivated again.
So how about it, Sensei?
Good grief. You sure are a tough nut to crack.
そこまでして、意地でも私の方を見ようとしないのは
先生としてのプライド…なんでしょうか？
How admirable.
Oh, no.
I think it's a good thing.
As a teacher, it's very praiseworthy.
But your ears...
are flush red.
That said,
it appears I'm also running out of gas.
もうこういうのやめて
だらけてしまいたいところなのですが
It appears our Sensei has an obsession for working.
I give up.
何があっても立ち上がらないと
となると
soudesune
Stay there and don't move an inch, Sensei.
There we go.
Hm?
「何」と言われましても
先生のオモリになって上げてるんですよ。
After all, it looks like your priorities
lie with work instead of your cute student.
I'm going to keep an eye on you
so that you don't run away
言い訳できないようにしてあげようかな〜
At least that's what I had in mind.
Hm?
What's wrong with that?
You get work done. Someone looks after you.
I get to loaf around.
That's three birds with one stone!
Is there something else troubling you?
私、結構軽い方だと思うんですけど
ならいいじゃないですか。
あとでやり返したりしないでくださいよ
この形なら良いですが
逆だとちょっと心配になるので
ほらほら、そんなこと言ってる場合ですか？
Instead of paying attention to me,
hurry up and get back to work.
"Don't slack off," right?
You made a mistake there.
Are you tallying up the wrong lines?
いいえ、大したことではないので。
The fact that you're starting to misread things
makes it pretty evident that you're tired.
少し休んだほうが、すっきりして
仕事の処理も早くなるかもしれませんよ？
まあ別に、私はこのままでも一向に構いませんが
大丈夫ですよ。
無理やり先生の体を同行
と言ったような直接的な邪魔をしませんので
触接的なものは、ですけどね？
By the way, I read in some book that
imperative statements in the negative tend to have
a boomerang effect on the brain.
For example、こうして「サボっちゃダメ」、
と言われると、「サボる」という単語の方が
脳に結びついて
離れなくなってしまうんだとか
So what I'm saying is, don't take a break.
Don't slack off.
Don't give in to Iroha.
Now, you'll start thinking,
"I wanna take a break,"
"I wanna slack off,"
"I wanna give in,"
as a result of your brain converting them.
私のことも「気にしない気にしない」と思ったところで
ほ〜ら、もう今既に逃げられなくなってるんじゃないですか？
この状況、先生はどこまで耐えられますかね？